

# Profile

I am fluent in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and experienced in back-end languages like PHP, NodeJS, and Python. I am currently working as the in-house developer for ManagedWay Company, an ISP located in Troy, MI. I have mainly designed, created, and supported web applications for them, and in addition to the above languages, I am proficient in MySQL, SQLite, and MongoDB. I graduated from Walsh College business school in June 2019 with a Bachelor's degree in I.T., focusing on Business Information Systems. In addition to its technical training, this degree has given me a strong insight into how the business and I.T. worlds connect.

# **Employment History**

### Software Developer at ManagedWay Company, Troy, MI

September 2019-Present

- Designed, created, and deployed a single pane of glass dashboard for our DDoS
  mitigation service customers. The application used JWT tokens as part of its rigorous
  authentication process. Additionally, it interacted with an ELK (Elasticsearch, Logstash,
  Kibana) cluster to pull data about how the service was working for them. A modern
  mobile-first UI and interactive graphs displayed the customer's data, and they also could
  print and download these reports as PDF files.
- Designed, created, deployed, and supported a mobile-first web application that could store our partner carriers' serviceable addresses. The program could import Excel files ranging from 5 MB to 250+ MB in size. I wrote the file import module in C to ensure the fastest processing of files. The addresses were stored and sorted by partner carrier in a central database and then made searchable via a PHP (later updated to NodeJS) backend.
- Designed, created, deployed, and supported a mobile-first single pane of glass application
  to store and make searchable all company info about customers, services, physical
  inventory, and more. The back-end used a relational MySQL database to store this data
  and the relationships between it.

#### IT Technician at Out of the Box Solutions, St. Clair Shores, MI

May 2018-September 2019

- Used Active Directory and Exchange to create new accounts and modify existing accounts
- Troubleshot end-user network issues using ping, traceroute, and port scanners
- Diagnosed scan-to-email enabled network printers and scanners
- Wrote scripts to automate administration duties

# Education History

Bachelor of I.T., majoring in Business Information Systems

September 2016-June 2019

Cisco Certified Entry Level Networking Technician Certificate

Received in August 2018

#### **Details**

Clinton Twp, MI (248) 915-4589

https://davidr.pro

david@davidr.pro

https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-ruffner/

https://github.com/davidruffner

Languages
HTML/CSS/JavaScript/jQuery
NodeJS

Python

PHP

MySQL/SQLite

MongoDB

C#

C

Skills
Communication/Soft Skills

Apache and Nginx

TCP/IP Networking

Hardware

Linux Sysadmin

Photoshop



## Set Buddy - In Progress

https://github.com/david-ruffner/setbuddy

## **Purpose**

This will be a fully featured web application designed for musicians who need to keep track of everything that they are practicing. The user will be able to keep track of the theory, scales, songs, and other assignments that they are practicing. An intelligent algorithm will allow for automatic generation of practice sets based on several factors including how important the a given song is, how well the user has been doing on the song, and how long they want a practice set to take. These sets can be manually adjusted, saved, printed off, and emailed as PDF files. The program will be cloud based, and will require the user to sign up with a valid e-mail address. All of their data will be stored in a cloud. There will also be an Android (and potentially an iOS) app that will include all of the features of the web app as well as extra utilities like a metronome.

#### **Main Features**

- Cloud based application that will automatically store user data.
- User will be able to keep track of their theory, scales, songs, and any other assignments.
- User will be able to keep track of how well they are doing on assignments over time, and this factor will play into the algorithm that creates automatic practice set lists.
- Android (and possibly an iOS) app will include all of the above features as well as extra utilities such as a metronome.
- A modern and scalable design so that the web-app can be used effectively on any sized device.

## Languages

- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/jQuery for the web app's front-end
- The back-end will use a MySQL database to store the user data, and will use NodeJS to create REST API for interacting with the data. This will allow both the web app and the Android/iOS app to use one unified API for accessing user data.
- Kotlin to create the Android app
- Swift to create the iOS app